A Guide to the Papers of Emily Couric, ca. 1983-2002
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series IV: Constituent Mail
  - Correspondence- Constituents Bovet- Busching, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 69:5)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Caldwell- Caughron, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 70:1)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Chafin- Clark, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 70:2)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Clatterbuck- Collier, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 70:3)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Collins- Courtney, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 70:4)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Cove- Cutright, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 70:5)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Dalton- Davis, R., 1995-2001 (Box-folder 71:1)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Davis, S.- Dogwood, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 71:2)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Dollins- Dunnivan, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 71:3)
  - Correspondence- Constituents E, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 71:4)
  - Correspondence- Constituents F, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 71:5)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Gallagher- Goodell, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 71:6)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Gooding- Graves, J., 1995-2001 (Box-folder 72:1)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Graves, P.- Gunter, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 72:2)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Haas- Harding, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 72:3)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Harlow- Hensley, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 72:4)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Herndon- Holley, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 72:5)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Hollowell- Hutson, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 72:6)
  - Correspondence- Constituents I, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 72:7)
  - Correspondence- Constituents James- Jones, H., 1995-2001 (Box-folder 73:1)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Jones, J.- Justus, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 73:2)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Kamei- Kyger, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 73:3)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Lackey- Lake, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 73:4)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Lamb- Lang, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 73:5)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Larie- Leake, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 73:6)
  - Correspondence- Constituents LeBovit- Lichtman, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 74:1)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Lightburn, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 74:2)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Lilleleht- Lynn, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 74:3)
  - Correspondence- Constituents McAllister- McElroy, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 74:4)
  - Correspondence- Constituents McFadden- McLernon, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 74:5)
  - Correspondence- Constituents McRaven- Massie, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 74:6)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Matano- Maxey, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 75:1)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Mayes- Middleditch, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 75:2)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Milani- Mills, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 75:3)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Mohler- Morris, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 75:4)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Moran- Musa, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 75:5)
  - Correspondence- Constituents N, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 75:6)
  - Correspondence- Constituents O, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 75:7)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Pace- Porter, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 75:8)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Post- Quinley, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 76:1)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Raisig- Reilly, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 76:2)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Reiss- Richardson, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 76:3)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Riehn- Rosenfield, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 76:4)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Rotgin- Rothberg, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 76:5)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Rothgeb- Rutherford, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 76:6)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Sadler- Schnoor, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 76:7)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Schwab- Slayton, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 77:1)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Smith, C.- Smith, M., 1995-2001 (Box-folder 77:2)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Smith, T.- Staggers, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 77:3)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Starling- Swofford, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 77:4)
  - Correspondence- Constituents T, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 77:5)
  - Correspondence- Constituents U-V, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 78:1)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Wade- Wilkie, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 78:2)
  - Correspondence- Constituents Willer-Willets, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 78:3)
  - Correspondence- Constituents- Williams -Wynn, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 78:4)
  - Correspondence- Constituents X-Z, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 78:5)
  - Sample Responses, 1997 (Box-folder 78:6)
- Series V: Speeches
  - Speeches, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 79:1)
    Interest Groups and Ideology (Spring 1994), Accepting the Nomination as the Democratic Candidate for the 25th District of the Senate of Virginia (May 16, 1995), The More General Diffusion of Knowledge- Curry School of Education Forum, University of Virginia (September 1995), Campaign Victory Speech (November 1995)
  - Speeches, 1996 January-May, Including: Getting the Best Return on your Educational Investment- Curry School of Education 6th Annual Student Leadership Conference (March 14, 1996), Our Schools, Our Future: The Debate Over Education- Curry School of Education (May 4, 1996). (Box-folder 79:2)
  - Speeches, 1996 June-December (Box-folder 79:3)
    Including: Graduation Speech- Charlottesville-Albemarle Technical Education Center (June 12, 1996), Nelson County High School Commencement Exercises (June 15, 1996), Orange County Special Education Workshop (1996), Curry School of Education Dinner (November 22, 1996).
  - Speeches, 1997 (Box-folder 79:3)
    Including: Red Cross Breakfast (March 19, 1997), Mary Baldwin College Commencement (May 25, 1997), Leadership 2000 Remarks Responsible Self-Governance (June 4, 1997), Our Government and Our Children: The Responsibilities and Limitations of Public Policy (September 4, 1997), Higher Education: Critical Issues for Virginia's Next Generation- Forum on Higher Education (October 2, 1997), The Final Exam: Dealing in Faith- Rosh Hashanah 5758 October 1997).
  - Speeches, 1998 January- July (Box-folder 79:4)
    Including: University of Virginia School of Nursing School Health Conference Keynote Address (March 7, 1998), Charlottesville Women's Forum Speech (March 20, 1998), Virginia Emergency Nurses Association- Legislators, Legislation, and Health Care Reform (March 24, 1998), Salvation Army Annual Dinner (March 24, 1998), Mid-Atlantic Association of Women in Law Enforcement 1998 Conference (April 6, 1998), University of Virginia Women Faculty and Professional Association and the Junior League of Charlottesville (April 9, 1998), Virginia Council Against Poverty (April 9, 1998), Nurses' Day Celebration, University of Virginia (May 6, 1998), Village School Commencement Address (June 4, 1998), Virginia Association of Assessing Officers (July 15, 1998).
  - Speeches, 1998 August-December (Box-folder 79:5)
    Including: Virginia Sheriffs Association Annual Conference (September 1998), Portsmouth Public Schools Back-to-School Convocation, (September 2, 1998), AARP Charlottesville-Albemarle Chapter Luncheon Meeting (September 3, 1998), The Role of State and Local Governments in the Support and Development of Technology Businesses- Charlottesville Venture Group (October 20, 1998), Page County Democratic Committee Dinner (October 22, 1998), Wise County Democratic Committee Luncheon (October 31, 1998), VA COOL Keynote Address- Changing the World, One Student at a Time (November 7, 1998), Downtown Charlottesville Speech (1998).
  - Speeches, 1999 (Box-folder 80:1)
    Including: Re-Election Campaign Announcement Speech (March 30, 1999), Charlottesville-Albemarle Technical Education Center (CATEC) Ceremony (April 22, 1999), Breast Health Coalition Recognition Breakfast (May 12, 1999), Remarks Upon Accepting the Democratic Nomination for the 25th District of the Senate of Virginia (May 26, 1999), Veterans of Foreign Wars Memorial Day Ceremony (May 31, 1999), Monticello High School Graduation (June 1999), Standards, School Reform and Equalizing Educational Opportunity in the Next Millennium Panel Discussion, Curry School of Education (July 7, 1999), Piedmont Environmental Council Annual Meeting (September 11, 1999), Youth Leadership Initiative Senate Candidate Debate (October 19, 1999), AARP Conference (November 1999), Virginia Cooperative Extension Leadership Council Fall District Meeting (November 11, 1999).
  - Speeches, 2000 January-May (Box-folder 80:2)
    Including: Third Regional Conference on Community Relations Keynote Luncheon Speech (May 4, 2000), Arlington Young Democrats 2000 Spring Banquet (May 11, 2000).
  - Speeches, 2000 June-December, Including: Democratic Party of Virginia Convention (June 2, 2000), Lee High School Graduation (June 3, 2000), Valleys of Virginia Luncheon (June 16, 2000), Remarks upon accepting the Distinguished Service Award from the American College of Gastroenterology (October 16, 2000), Computers, Connectivity, and Community- Connected Community Technology Center Grand Opening (October 18, 2000), Virginia Alliance of Family Child Care Associations 2000 Conference- Virginia Beach (October 28, 2000), Make a Difference Day Dinner to benefit Patient Support Services at the University of Virginia Cancer Center- Farmington Country Club (November 29, 2000). (Box-folder 80:3)
  - Speeches, 2001, n.d. (Box-folder 80:4)
    Including: The Role of Government in Protecting Individuals Against Genetic Discrimination- University of Virginia School of Medicine (March 30, 2001), Knickerbocker Luncheon (September 20, 2001), Speech on Education (n.d.), Speech on Education- Reference Materials.
  - Speeches, n.d. (Box-folder 80:5)
    Including: Phi Delta Kappa Initiation Remarks, Downtown Charlottesville Speech, Education Funding, Rural Preservation Speech, Roast of L.F. Payne.
  - Speeches- Speechwriting- Reference Materials, 1987-1999, n.d. (Box-folder 80:6)
  - Speeches- Speechwriting- Gregory A. Werkheiser, 1995-2000 (Box-folder 80:7)
- Series XI: Audiovisual Materials
  - Subseries A. Legislative
    - Senate of Virginia, 1997 January 28 (Videocassette 0136.)
    - Senate of Virginia, 1997 February 20 (Videocassette 0137.)
    - Senate of Virginia- Tape 1 of 3, 2000 March 8 (Videocassette 0138.)
    - Senate of Virginia- Tape 2 of 3, 2000 March 8 (Videocassette 0138-a.)
    - Senate of Virginia- Tape 3 of 3, 2000 March 8 (Videocassette 0138-b.)
    - Senate of Virginia- Tape 1 of 2, 2001 February 2 (Videocassette 0139.)
    - Senate of Virginia- Tape 1 of... Includes a note by Dr. George A. Beller, 2001 February 6 (Videocassette 0140.)
    - Senate of Virginia- Tape 2 of 3, 2001 February 6 (Videocassette 0140-a.)
    - Senate, Tape #2, 2001 February 19 (Videocassette 0141.)
    - Senate, Tape #2, 2001 February 21 (Videocassette 0142.)
    - Senate of Virginia, Tape 1 of 3, 2001 February 22 (Box-folder Videocassette 0143.)
    - Senate of Virginia, Includes a note by Dr. George A. Beller, Tape 1 of 2, 2002 January 10 (Videocassette 0144.)
    - Senate of Virginia, Tape 2 of 2, 2002 January 10 (Videocassette 0144-a.)
    - Legislature Session- Bills, #1, 2000 February 4 (Videocassette 0145.)
    - Legislature Session- Bills, #2, 2000 February 4 (Videocassette 0145-a.)
    - Cable Reports from the General Assembly- Senator Couric, Delegate Abbit, 1999 February 16 (Videocassette 0146.)
    - Cable Reports from the General Assembly- Senator Couric, Delegate Abbit, n.d. (Videocassette 0146-a.)
    - Irv Hill- Cable Reports, General Assembly, n.d. (Videocassette 0147.)
    - Irv Hill- Cable Reports, General Assembly- Senator Couric, Delegate Van Yahres, and Delegate Harris, n.d. (Videocassette 0147-a.)
    - The Virginia Assembly Review '95: A News Program summarizing the 1995 General Assembly Session, 1995 (Videocassette 0148.)
    - The Virginia Assembly Report '95, 1995 (Videocassette 0148-a.)
  - Subseries B.: Couric for Senate
    - VCTA Charlottesville- Adelphia Cable Reports Couric, 2000 March 9 (Videocassette 0148-b.)
    - Doak Carrier & Associates- Emily Couric for State Senate Modern Video Productions, 1995 September 7 (Videocassette 0149.)
    - Doak Carrier & Associates- Emily Couric for State Senate- Response Modern Video Productions, 1995 October 19 (Videocassette 0149-a.)
    - Doak, Carrier & Associates, Emily Couric for State Senate, Correction Henninger Video, 1995 October 26 (Videocassette 0149-b.)
    - Doak, Carrier & Associates, Emily Couric for State Senate, Correction (duplicate) Henninger Video, 1995 October 26 (Videocassette 0149-c.)
    - Doak, Carrier & Associates, Emily Couric for State Senate, Endorsed Henninger Video, 1995 October 31 (Videocassette 0149-d.)
    - Doak Carrier & Associates, Emily Couric for State Senate,- Endorse revised- Modern Video Productions, 1995 November 2 (Videocassette 0149-e.)
    - Emily Couric for State Senate Revised Henninger Video: Arlington, 1999 September 13 (Videocassette 0149-f.)
  - Subseries C. Other Politics
    - Emily Couric- Politics- E. R. Trial, WTVR, 1993 June 22 (Videocassette 0150.)
    - Crime Forum (Videocassette 0151), 1995 September 13 (Videocassette 0151.)
    - This Week in Richmond: Flag Bill, 1999 November 24 (Videocassette 0152.)
  - Subseries D. Presentation and Demo s
    - Zimmerman & Markman, INC 1999 Presentation, 1999 (Videocassette 0153.)
    - ESI Productions, ESI Demo, n.d. (Videocassette 0153-a.)
    - ESI Productions, Emily Couric Campaign Kickoff raw footage, 1994 November 18 (Videocassette 0153-b.)
  - Subseries E. Memorial and Tributes
    - Larry King Live- Dan Rather Tribute to Emily, 2001 October 18 (Videocassette 0154.)
    - Master #2- Memorial Service for Emily Couric; Includes note by Dr. George A. Beller, 2001 October 22 (Videocassette 0154-a.)
    - Channel 29 Coverage, 2001 October 18 (Videocassette 0154-b.)
  - Subseries F. National Television
    - NBC Willard Scott Segment, 1993 November 12 (Videocassette 0155.)
    - [Phil] Donahue with Emily Couric, 1995 October 19 (Videocassette 0155-a.)
  - Subseries G. Miscellaneous
    - Man with a Plan, a film by John O'Brian (about Fred Tuttle, congressional candidate), n.d. (Videocassette 0156.)
    - Emily Couric, Batesville Ruritan Club meeting, Mt. Ed Baptist Church, 1995 September 21 (Videocassette 0157.)
  - Subseries H. Public Television
    - Consider This Senator Emily Couric- WPTV, 1999 (Videocassette 0158.)
    - Consider This Senator Emily Couric- WPTV, 2000 (Videocassette 0158-a.)
    - Consider This Senator Emily Couric- WPTV, n.d. (Videocassette 0158-b.)
    - Children's Medical Center 7th Floor Live, 1996 December 5 (Videocassette 0158-d.)
  - Subseries I. Medical
    - American College of Gastroenterology, ACG Newsline- New York Program 2, 2000 October 16 (Videocassette 0159.)
    - Commonwealth Neurotrauma Initiative, n. d. (Videocassette 0159-a.)
  - Subseries J. Politics General
    - Sorensen Institute Promotional (Video: Institute for Political Leadership at the University of Virginia), 2001 October (Videocassette 0160.)
  - Subseries K. Debates
    - Ed Robb- Cable Access, n.d. (Videocassette 0161.)
    - Channel 29: 6pm and 11pm Local News Debate: Ed Robb, n.d. (Videocassette 0161-a.)
    - Debate: Ed Robb & others Live- Larry Sabato- WVTF 89, n.d. (Videocassette 0161-b.)
    - Harris Wayland and 1st Annual Youth Leadership Initiative, n.d. (Videocassette 0161-c.)
    - 2nd Annual Youth Leadership Initiative, Debate between Emily Couric and Jane Maddox, n.d. (Videocassette 0161-d.)
  - Subseries L. Education
    - Monticello High School- Emily Couric Introduction, n.d. (Videocassette 0162.)
    - Public Education in Virginia- Copy for Dr. Bunch, Add. Vid. Prod., n.d. (Videocassette 0163.)
    - International Soccer and Local News Story, Channel 29 Interview with Emily Couric, [1994-1995] (Videocassette 0164.)